Guide to the Hound & Horn Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Hound & Horn records
1925-1940
YCAL MSS 458
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.13
(8 boxes)
The Hound & Horn records contain correspondence, drafts of writings, financial records, and ephemera relating to the literary quarterly. The records feature original letters from well-known Modernist era authors during the tenure of the journal from the late 1920s through mid 1930s, including Bryher, Jean Cocteau, E. E. Cummings, René Daumal, T. S. Eliot, Ernest Hemingway, François Mauriac, Marianne Moore, Ezra Pound, Stephen Spender, Gertrude Stein, Robert Penn Warren, William Carlos Williams, and Louis Zukosfky, among others. There are also letters from publishers and editors, copies of outgoing letters, third-party letters, financial and legal records, and scattered drafts. There are drafts, some corrected, of work by Cummings, Daumal, Bernard Faÿ, Varian Fry, James Hanley, Pound, Spender, and Williams. The Pound files contain corrected typescript drafts for Cantos XXVIII, XXIX, XXX.
Hound & Horn
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lincoln Kirstein, 1982.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Hound & Horn
The Hound & Horn was a literary quarterly founded by Harvard students Lincoln Kirstein and Varian Fry in 1927. Modeled on T. S. Eliot's The Criterion, it was intended to focus on student life at Harvard and work submitted by its students and alumni. The publication later broadened in scope to include modern writers. The title of the magazine was taken from Ezra Pound's poem "The White Stag": "Tis the white stag, Fame, we're a hunting, bid the world's hounds come to horn." R. P. Blackmur served as the magazine's first managing editor from 1928 to 1930, when the magazine moved its headquarters to New York. Hound & Horn ceased publication in 1934.
Scope and Contents
The Hound & Horn records contain correspondence, drafts of manuscripts, financial records, and ephemera relating to the literary quarterly. The records feature original letters from well-known Modernist era authors during the tenure of the journal from the late 1920s through mid 1930s, including Bryher, Jean Cocteau, E. E. Cummings, René Daumal, T. S. Eliot, Ernest Hemingway, François Mauriac, Marianne Moore, Ezra Pound, Stephen Spender, Gertrude Stein, Robert Penn Warren, William Carlos Williams, and Louis Zukofsky, among others. There are also letters from publishers and editors, copies of outgoing letters, third-party letters, financial and legal records, and scattered drafts. There are drafts, some corrected, for work by Cummings, Daumal, Bernard Fay, Varian Fry, James Hanley, Pound, Spender, and Williams. The Pound files, for example, contain corrected typescript drafts for Cantos XXVIII, XXIX, XXX.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Correspondence, 1925-1940. II. Other Materials, 1927-1934.
Hound & horn; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Little magazines -- Archives; Publishers and publishing; Authors; Bryher, 1894-1983; Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963; Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962; Daumal, René, 1908-1944; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Faÿ, Bernard, 1893-1978; Fry, Varian, 1907-1967; Hanley, James, 1897-1985; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961; Kirstein, Lincoln, 1907-1996; Mauriac, François, 1885-1970; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963; Zukofsky, Louis, 1904-1978
- Correspondence, 1925-1940; Series I; 2.92; (7 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by name or subject.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, contains original letters from well-known Modernist era authors during the tenure of the journal from the late 1920s through mid 1930s, including Bryher, Jean Cocteau, E. E. Cummings, René Daumal, T. S. Eliot, Ernest Hemingway, Francois Mauriac, Marianne Moore, Ezra Pound, Stephen Spender, Gertrude Stein, Robert Penn Warren, William Carlos Williams, and Louis Zukofsky, among others. In addition to the incoming letters of authors, there are letters from publishers and editors, copies of outgoing letters in selected files, third-party letters, financial and legal records, and scattered drafts.
  Manuscript drafts are documented in folder notes.
  - "A" general, 1925 (Box 1)
  - "B" general, 1927-1933 (Box 1)
  - Babbitt, Irving, undated (Box 1)
  - Bandler, Bernard, 1932-1938, undated (Box 1)
  - Beach, Sylvia, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1934, undated (Box 1)
  - Beverley, E. H., 1933-1936 (Box 1)
  - Birss, John, 1931-1935 (Box 1)
  - Blackmur, R. P., 1935 September 26 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, Louise, undated (Box 1)
    Includes draft of short story "The Cornerstone"
  - Bryher, W., 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Burnham, James, 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - "C" general, 1927-1934 (Box 1)
  - Calder, Alexander, undated (Box 1)
  - Caldwell, Erskine, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Cocteau, Jean, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Code, Grant H., 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - Colum, Padraic, 1932 June 13 (Box 1)
  - Coppard, A. E., 1930 August 22 (Box 1)
  - Cowell, Henry, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Crane, Grace (Hart), 1934 (Box 1)
  - Crosby, Harry, 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Cummings, E. E., 1932-1934 (Box 1)
    Includes drafts
  - "D" general, 1928-1932, undated (Box 1)
  - Daumal, René, 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - Dwiggins, W. A., 1930 January 4 (Box 1)
  - "E" general, 1927-1929 (Box 1)
  - Eliot, T. S., 1927-1932 (Box 1)
  - "F" general, 1927-1933 (Box 1)
  - Fay, Bernard, undated (Box 1)
    Contains draft of "Sur le bon usage litteraire de la jeunesse"
  - Financial correspondence and records, 1927-1933; 4 (Box 1)
  - Financial correspondance and records, 1934-1938, undated; 6 (Box 2)
  - Fitts, Dudley, 1929-1934; 3 (Box 2)
  - Fry, Varian, undated (Box 2)
    Contains draft of "Mr. Fry's Song of Spring"
  - "G" general, 1928-1936 (Box 2)
  - Garnett, David, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Gold, Mike, undated (Box 2)
  - Gould, Joe, 1933 (Box 2)
  - "H" general, 1927-1932 (Box 2)
  - Hanley, James, undated (Box 2)
    Includes drafts of "The Last Voyage" and "Stoker Haslett"
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Hitchcock, Henry Russell, 1929 (Box 2)
  - "J" general, 1929-1937 (Box 2)
  - Jacobs, S. A., 1931-1932 (Box 2)
  - James, Henry, 1934, undated (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Josephine W., 1932 (Box 2)
  - Jolas, Eugene, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Jones, Robert Edmund, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Joyce, James, 1931-1932 (Box 2)
  - "K" general, 1927-1934 (Box 3)
  - Kenton, Edna, 1931-1934 (Box 3)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, undated (Box 3)
  - Krinkin, David and Lydia, 1934-1935 (Box 3)
  - "L" general, 1927-1934, undated (Box 3)
  - La Driere, Craig, 1930-1933 (Box 3)
  - Lane, James W., 1929 (Box 3)
  - Larsson, R. Ellsworth, 1929-1934 (Box 3)
  - Laughlin, James, 1933, undated (Box 3)
  - Lawrence, Thomas E., 1934-1939 (Box 3)
  - Legal correspondence and records, 1927-1938, undated; 11 (Box 3)
  - Lerner, Irving, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
  - Linscott, Robert, 1929-1940; 2 (Box 4)
  - The Lion and the Unicorn, 1934, undated (Box 4)
  - Lowenfels, Walter, 1933 (Box 4)
  - Lozowick, Lewis, 1930-1933 (Box 4)
  - "M" general, 1927-1934, undated (Box 4)
  - McAlmon, Robert, 1929-1930 (Box 4)
  - Macdonald, Dwight, 1929 (Box 4)
  - McHugh, Vincent, 1933 (Box 4)
  - McKeon, Richard P., 1929 (Box 4)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1931-1934 (Box 4)
  - MacLeod, Norman, 1930-1934 (Box 4)
  - The Magazine, 1933-1935 (Box 4)
  - Manach, Jorge, 1929 (Box 4)
  - Manchester, Frederick A., 1932 (Box 4)
  - Mangan, Sherry, 1929-1930 (Box 4)
  - March, William, 1930-1933 (Box 4)
  - Mauriac, François, 1930, November 3 (Box 4)
  - Mayor, A. Hyatt, 1929-1934, undated (Box 4)
  - Miller, Ward M., 1930, undated (Box 4)
  - Monroe, Harriet, 1932 (Box 4)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1931-1934 (Box 4)
  - Morris, G. L. K., 1933, undated (Box 4)
  - Mortimer, Raymond, 1930 (Box 4)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1931 (Box 4)
  - Munson, Gorham, 1929-1935 (Box 4)
  - "N" general, 1928-1933, undated (Box 4)
  - Neagoe, Peter, 1930 (Box 4)
  - The New English Weekly, 1932-1933, undated (Box 4)
  - The New Republic, 1932, undated (Box 4)
  - New Verse, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
  - Nomad, Max, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
  - "O" general, 1929-1932 (Box 4)
  - O'Brien, Edward J., 1929-1934 (Box 4)
  - O'Brien, Justin, 1929-1933 (Box 4)
  - O'Faolain, Sean, 1929-1933 (Box 4)
  - Oppenheimer, Robert, 1930-1932, undated (Box 4)
  - Orrick, James Bentley, 1929-1934 (Box 4)
  - Oxford University Press, 1930 April (Box 4)
  - "P" general, 1928-1933, undated (Box 5)
  - Parkes, Henry Bamford, 1931, undated (Box 5)
  - Parry, Albert, 1932-1933 (Box 5)
  - Patchen, Kenneth, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
  - Pegis, Anton C., 1931-1932 (Box 5)
  - Perkins, Maxwell, 1931 (Box 5)
  - Pickman, Hester, 1929-1931, undated (Box 5)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1929-1934 (Box 5)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1929-1934; 8 (Box 5)
    Includes drafts of "Criterionism" and "Cantos XXVIII, XXIX, XXX"
  - Quennel, Peter, 1930-1938, undated (Box 5)
  - "R" general, 1930-1934, undated (Box 5)
  - Rakosi, Carl, 1931-1932, undated (Box 5)
  - Ramsey, John, 1933-1935 (Box 5)
  - Ranck, Carty, 1932 January 12 (Box 5)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, 1929-1931 (Box 5)
  - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Roditi, Edouard, 1931-1932, undated (Box 5)
  - Rodman, Selden, 1931-1934, undated (Box 5)
  - Rosenberg, Harold, 1929-1934 (Box 5)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1931 (Box 5)
  - Ross, Cary, 1932-1935 (Box 5)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1932-1933 (Box 5)
  - "S" general, 1928-1934, undated; 2 (Box 5)
  - Saturday Review of Literature, 1933, undated (Box 5)
  - Saunders, Sylvia, 1934 (Box 5)
  - Saurat, Denis, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Schafer, Robert, 1929-1930 (Box 5)
  - Scheiwiller, Giovanni, 1931 (Box 5)
  - Scott, Winfred T., 1932-1933 (Box 5)
  - Sessions, Roger, 1931-1933 (Box 6)
  - Siegel, Eli, 1930-1931 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Robert M., 1933-1935, undated (Box 6)
  - Spencer, Theodore, 1933 (Box 6)
  - Spender, Steven, 1933-1938; 2 (Box 6)
    Includes drafts of "The Burning Cactus" and "The Strange Death"
  - Stanford, Donald, 1933-1934 (Box 6)
  - Stein, Gertrude, 1932-1934 (Box 6)
  - Stevens, George, 1931-1934 (Box 6)
  - Stevens, Wallace, 1929-1931 (Box 6)
  - "T" general, 1927-1941, undated (Box 6)
  - Tate, Allen, 1929-1934; 3 (Box 6)
  - Taylor, Prentiss, undated (Box 6)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1933 (Box 6)
  - Tichenor, George, 1931-1934 (Box 6)
  - Toomer, Jean, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Trask, Sherwood, 1931-1933 (Box 6)
  - Troy, William, 1932-1934 (Box 6)
  - "U" general, 1928-1933 (Box 6)
  - "V" general, 1928-1932 (Box 6)
  - Van der Post, Laurens, 1933-1935, undated (Box 6)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, 1933-1934 (Box 6)
  - "W" general, 1927-1937, undated (Box 7)
  - Wadsworth, P. Beaumont, 1930, undated (Box 7)
  - Walker, Charles R., 1930 (Box 7)
  - Warren, Austin, 1930-1932, undated (Box 7)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1932-1933 (Box 7)
  - Weiser, Elliot, 1929-1930 (Box 7)
  - Weiss, Paul, 1931 (Box 7)
  - Werner, M. R., 1932-1934 (Box 7)
  - Wheelwright, John B., 1929-1940 (Box 7)
  - Whitall, James, 1929-1930 (Box 7)
  - White, Kenneth, 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1929-1931, undated (Box 7)
    Includes draft of "In the 'Sconset Bus"
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1929-1934 (Box 7)
  - Wilson, T.C., 1931-1933 (Box 7)
  - Winters, Yvor, 1929-1934, undated; 7 (Box 7)
  - Wood, Richardson King, undated (Box 7)
    Contains draft of "Reception to the Ambassador"
  - "Y" general, 1928-1932 (Box 7)
  - Young, Kathleen Tankerslay, 1930-1933 (Box 7)
  - Young, Stark, 1931-1934 (Box 7)
  - "Z" general, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Zabel, Morton Dauwin, 1931-1937 (Box 7)
  - Zukofsky, Louis, 1929-1931; 2 (Box 7)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 7)
- Other Materials, 1927-1934; Series II; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by material type.
  Series II, Other Materials, consists of finanical records, such as checks, ledgers, and tax statements, and printed ephemera.
  - Financial records, 1927-1934, undated (Box 8)
  - Printed ephemera, 1930, undated (Box 8)